Adam is probably the best founder no
one's ever heard of. There's an ad
platform hiding inside 100,000 mobile
games and is quietly outperforming
Facebook ads for e-commerce brands. Of
all those thousand plus IPOs, the number
one most valuable is AppL. Appe.
The founder mentality has got to be
Chase winning.
>> They're going to print something like $6
billion in cash this year.
>> In a world where things don't make
sense, people think you're cheating.
instead of realizing you built one of
the cooler technologies the world's ever
seen.
>> Please welcome Adam Farugi.
>> All right. Welcome, Adam. Hey, man.
>> Big man.
>> How you doing, bro? Good to see you.
Likewise.
>> Adam, thanks for being here. Um, we
thought it'd be really great to chat
because a lot of people don't talk as
much about you're not in the headlines
all the time with your business. You're
operating your business almost like
absent media. You don't do a lot of
press. You don't get out there a lot
talking about the company, but it's such
an incredible business. Can you just
tell the audience kind of what Apploving
is and maybe also frame up the market a
little bit for us?
>> Yeah, totally. I I think the the fact
that we were able to build a very big
company without having VC funding at the
early stage created this world where we
just had to build quietly and and then
obviously the goofy name didn't help us
all that much as well. But what we are
ultimately is an advertising company
that's helping mobile game developers
monetize that space. Now what people
don't realize is just how big the mobile
gaming universe has become. You've got
over a billion people a day playing
mobile casual games. These are all
adults, heads of households, and the
scale of the opportunity is just
humongous. We disclosed last January, so
nearly two years ago, that on our own
platform, there was 11 billion a year of
ad spend. Since then, we've grown 60%
year-over-year roughly. And so, if you
gross that up to a nice round number
today, you get 20 billion. Now, we're
not the only player in this marketplace.
This is a market that's monetized by a
lot of other ad companies as well. So
then you'd probably more than double
that again and round it off and say
there's probably about $50 billion of
advertising being spent every single
year in this mobile gaming ecosystem. It
was not very long ago that social was a
$50 billion opportunity. Space is
growing really quickly. A lot of
audience these people watch ads. They a
lot of times they watch the ads to get
rewards. And so that dynamic creates
this possibility to create intent. For
the most of the LE company's life, we've
been creating that intent to drive a
user to take one game's experience and
go to the next games experience. And
what's really gotten investors excited
about our company and just us excited
about the opportunity that we we have in
front of us is that deep learning models
have gotten so so powerful now that you
could take that same space and try to
take that adult and give them a shopper
behavior experience. And that allows us
to tap into much larger economies, make
more of an economic impact in the world.
And that's why our team's just really
really pumped up on what we're doing.
>> The the first wave of internet
advertising was in many ways the spark
for a lot of critical technologies that
then sort of diffused out into the
world. So like if you think what Google
was able to do with Adwords, AdSense,
applied semantics, all of that whole
range of technology. Is that true in
this generation of internet advertising?
Are there are there technologies and
things that are being birthed here that
are consequential and foundational now
to the rest of the internet?
>> Yeah, I mean advertising is like ML 1.0
but really was the first implementation
of all these technologies that now are
are driving AI today and the the
economic value of a large language model
and what it's doing in our society today
is much greater than advertising. But
advertising is a very profitable
implementation of a deep learning model.
Now recommendation systems are
structured differently than large
language models but a lot in a lot of
ways they follow the same trajectory. So
a lot of the research that's being done
in the space in the large language model
space can port to recommendation systems
and vice versa. A lot of the researchers
in the large language model space might
have started early in their careers
looking at advertising systems. So these
two spaces are really related. The nice
thing about our business and any
advertising business is that when you
build a model, you're predicting a
future outcome, an advertisement, or if
you're building a social network, an
engagement post, or a sequence of them,
but you can translate the value of that
prediction immediately.
>> Is it is it true that there's just a
broad-based behavior around humans
reaction to ads in 2026 versus 2006?
Like, has there been an evolutionary arc
that's very predictive?
>> Yeah, it's it's interesting. I started
my career in 2005, so I saw the ads back
then, complete garbage. It was all spam
and the technologies just weren't
powerful enough. And your old company,
Facebook, did a really good job of
realizing if you can take all the data
we have in front of us and pair it with
good technology, the ads can become
really relevant. And if you talk to most
people who shop today, most of their
shopping recommendations are coming from
Instagram. The ads have become very much
like content. And in our domain as well,
people love the ads that we show. And
you would think people wouldn't like
them, but we see tons of engagement on
little mini games that are appearing in
other games. And people are playing
these previews because the technologies
have gotten so good at recommending
something relevant to someone.
>> There's been a lot of hand ringing about
the impact AI will have on
um the ad networks, specifically
Google's interface. And OpenAI has an ad
product now. I'm sure you've been
monitoring it uh and trying to learn
from it. What is advertising going to
look like when people are doing five or
six queries with a chatbot? Because it's
pretty obvious 95% of the world are not
going to pay 20 bucks a month for this
technology. They're going to expect it
to be free. Chat GPT has already said
they're going to make it free. Tell us
what they're doing in advertising. And
is it going to be less effective each
time, but in aggregate people are going
to use it more, or is it going to just
be even better than Google searches
franchise?
>> Yeah, I mean there's two sides of
advertising. One one part of it is
bottom offunnel advertising where a
consumer sort of knows what they want to
buy, but they're doing research to go
complete the transaction. And that's
Google search business. If I wanted to
buy a pair of dress shoes, go to Google
historically, do some research, and they
direct me to where I need to go based on
the ads. And today you can go to a large
language model and close the loop on
that same thing. So that ads model is
almost going to exclusively compete with
the Google search business. What we
operate in is a world where we're
showing a user an ad and we don't know
what their intent is. So we're trying to
create something that that didn't exist
before. Show them a recommendation and
get them to go, "Wow, that looks really
cool. Let me go transact on that and do
it really quickly." That that's what
drives Facebook's ad business, too. And
so the reason that's interesting to me
is that the transaction via search or LM
was going to happen anyways. If the LM
didn't exist and Google ads had never
come to existence, but Google search
existed, that transaction, the closed
loop would have happened. So there's not
actually a whole lot of economic
expansion that happens from that. But
when you show a consumer an ad for
something that they had no idea existed,
they didn't know they needed to buy.
>> Discovery basically,
>> totally complete discovery. And this is
what makes Meta so amazing in their ad
business and what we aspire to do. You
create that discovery moment. Not only
is it a really fun moment for the
consumer cuz then they're excited about
what they bought, they wait for the
package, they're excited to open it up,
but you create economic expansion. What
about the the arms race that develops
over time where
some people say, you know, I mention
something
with my friends at lunch and all of a
sudden I show up and there are these ads
on Meta or wherever. Is that just us
overreacting or is that is that actually
happening? And is there a push
not to be more um not intrusive but you
know like the tendency to want to sell
more?
>> That's creepy.
>> Yeah, it feels creepy when it does
happen
>> or just to push the boundaries at him.
Like what what is actually happening
when people say I say something at lunch
and all of a sudden an ad for that same
thing appears.
>> I mean I I think you've done other
actions that are trackable like do a
search, browse a website, do a product
search and you don't realize it and then
you say something related to and you
start seeing ads that are relevant. So,
it's not like the mic is on or there's
an app that has actually taken space.
>> There's a theory though that if we were
all at lunch, especially with these
apps, you know, our geol location,
you've kind of put us into a group. So,
we might be talking about this new car
we're all interested in or watch. And
then Freeberg, when he's leaving
searches for the watch to bookmark it
after the conversation, but you're
tracking all of our locations, and then
you say, "Okay, let's give all four of
them the ads for the watch." and you're
mix and matching based on
>> is that what's happening? That's what
I'm told.
>> I don't think advertising companies can
track location. So, we don't track
location at all. It's a really heavy
concept to track people's precise
location to then run render an ad. And
then to imagine the amount of data
that's transferring if you're mic to
then parse the mic on content to try to
translate to an ad. Not realistic.
>> But what about us being friends and
being connected together like groups?
>> So, we wouldn't have that data. But if
you're on a social network, of course,
your relationships together might drive
an ad experience. If Chimoth searches
for something, then you might see
something relevant to it. There's
nothing wrong with that. I mean, the one
thing that people lose there there's a
creepy factor that scares people
somewhat, but all of the data collected
at this point, given the scale of
advertising across all these companies,
is pretty much controlled in a lot of
ways. What people then forget is the
economic value that's created from these
ads becoming that relevant. that ad that
you saw, you recognize that ad. 20 years
ago, you would not have recognized the
ad. And there's a big part of GDP that's
now coming from this digital ad economy.
The better these technologies get,
faster GDP growth.
>> Adam, let's just go back to the um
because what I find so fascinating about
the business is the the the way you've
operated it. You're you're based in LA.
Is that right?
>> I'm based in LA. Company started in
Silicon Valley. We're in Palo Alto.
>> Palo Alto. But you're here and then you
have a lot of developers in China. Is
that right?
>> We have our engineering offices are in
Palo Alto, um, Beijing and Singapore.
>> And then the company didn't raise a lot
of venture money. You take the company
public 2021. It went public like 20
billion market cap out the gate.
>> Yeah, we were co IPO. We went out in
April 2021. Uh, it was about $28
billion.
>> 28 billion. And then in 2023, what did
the market cap collapse to? Well, this
is the funny thing about the public
market. So, we went out in 2021, $600
million of Ebida, $28 billion market
cap. We got as high as 40 billion. And
then in 22, the stock went down
literally every day. We got to about a
$3.8 billion market cap. In that year,
we did a billion dollars in IBIDA.
>> That's incredible.
>> So, so hold on. So, so, so, so let's
just go through this. So, the market's
in disbelief for some reason about the
business. And what do you do?
>> Yeah. What what you learn pretty quickly
and I'm a finance background so I had
good education on this is that your
price in the markets is determined by
the quality of your investors and we had
private market investors both private
equity and and ex-coounders and other
team members that were going to sell
when we went public and because there
were so many companies going public
during co by the time we went out blue
chip investors weren't doing the
research to figure out what is this
goofy named company so we ended up with
no demand and a lot of supply and That
construct created this world where we
just tanked and multiple went from
fairly high I mean I wouldn't really
value companies on 50 times ebata but to
something that was absurdly low sub four
times. So being that finance-minded
person, you have to remember with that
kind of a bashing, you do have an
opportunity on the other side of it. And
I turned in internal to the team and
said, I'm not going to talk to investors
at all anymore. They're not buying our
stock. It's a waste of time. But guess
what? We generated a ton of cash. Let's
start buying our own stock. Let's become
our best investor. So we kicked off a
super aggressive buyback program. And in
over the since then, I think we bought
roughly $6 billion of the company's
stock. um retired 20 to 25% of the
shares outstanding. At peak that six
billion was worth over 50 billion. And
so you can take that moment which does
feel super depressing and turn it into a
huge
>> How did you manage Sorry. Did you feel
that way from the like the whole time or
was there this period of depression
where you're like
>> oh my gosh what that's what I was going
to ask. How do you manage the internal
culture
>> when the stock is off 92%.
>> It's tough. I mean, like I'll tell you,
like I would get phone calls from family
members, friends, are you suicidal? And
I'm like, look, we we got stuck at a
penny. The stock's still like 10 bucks.
It's still up a lot. But it's very tough
then because you realize as a CEO, your
team is getting those same phone calls
from their family members.
>> Exly. And they don't have the the
gravitas that you do, nor the ownership.
>> So, so we built it by just saying,
"Look, it's an us against the world
mentality." Like, everyone's turned
against us. we're going to buy back
shares and we implemented a a
performance stock plan which typically
goes to CEOs but we did it across key
people in the company and said you know
we understand is tough right now we
understand you thought you had a house
and now you don't but if you dig in and
we recover you're going to make a ton on
the upside
>> and then what investors started showing
up and saying hey we're paying attention
again it
>> it was interesting because for us what
happened was we went from ML 1.0 like we
talked about a couple minutes ago to
ML2.0 We we went from a regression model
to a deep learning model and the outcome
was we're driven by our advertising
algorithm. The better it works, the
better advertiser return is on our
platform and everything is performance
based. So we're selling revenue to
advertisers, the more they scale. And so
the company just started growing really
quickly. Now we turned into 23 and
launched that model in April. We still
weren't talking to investors. So people
hadn't found out. And then it was
somewhere around I think September of 23
that I went to New York and I said the
stock's now like 80 bucks and we'd
recovered quite a bit cuz performance
was good. But I said I'm going to start
talking to investors cuz market cap's
getting high enough and we can't really
buy back all that aggressively anymore.
And in that week, the stock went from 80
to 150. And I think it was like 28
billion to 55 billion from you being in
New York.
>> From me just going out and saying, "Hey,
>> our company still exists. We survived
this."
>> Yeah. And then people like I'd sit in
the meetings and do like it's pretty
easy to read the other side of the room
if you you do that kind of thing. Sell
your company. I sit in the meetings. I'm
like these people are literally calling
their friends in the room going bye bye
bye bye bye. And I was like ah.
>> And then what's what's the opposite side
of that? Once they're long, are they now
asking you, "Okay, Adam, how do we
expand? How do we grow faster? Why just
games? Why not e-commerce? Why not this?
Why not that?" Absolutely. Damned if you
do, damned if you don't.
>> So, unfortunately, not a lot of people
are contrarians. So, you can go to the
extreme down and then on the other side
of it, you can go extreme up, too. We
ended up going from $9 to $750 a share
in a matter of 2 and 1/2 years. And so,
like, it was like a $3.8 billion market
cap. Some people bought some options
back then and were probably living in
some massive homes and we got to $250
billion market cap. So extreme on both
ends. We've now settled into a place
where we have a lot of excitement about
our growth opportunities. But I found
public market investors are not all that
different than private market investors.
They follow trends but a lot of times
later than you'd want. The most
sophisticated hit those trends early.
And that's why you have you have really
good VCs and you have average VCs. You
have really good public market
investors. You have average public
market investors.
>> Maybe you could talk a little bit about
privacy. Apple, the EU really are look
at companies like yours um and they this
is a little too aggressive in terms of
the data you're collecting. Some video
game developers don't like having data
collected on their users and and they've
tightened the screws a bit. Zuckerberg
had to deal with it specifically. So
what's the headwind on this business and
and how do you manage privacy when Apple
really is trying to let's call it what
it is they're trying to new to your
business. Look look in any of these
spaces you want the regulations to be
clear. So once they're clear technology
can deal with them and so if you could
precisely target a user 5 years ago on
iOS and today someone says I don't want
you to precisely target me you group
them in a in a bunch and you serve them
a worse advertisement. Now, the funny
outcome of that is we'll get a lot of
complaints after that change that Apple
made from users that say, "Serve me more
relevant ads. You're showing me a bunch
of spam." So, there is this notion that
you need privacy regulation so that
technology companies can do exactly
what's expected of them. On the other
side, consumers do want relevant ads. It
helps them discover products. If you're
sitting there in a game and you're
watching an ad for 30 seconds to get a
free life, you're getting something that
has monetary value. Now, if you're doing
that, do you want to sit and watch
garbage for 30 seconds or do you want to
watch something relevant? And so, what's
what's happened since a lot of the
privacy noise is a lot of comm the rules
were written, technology companies have
adapted and deep learning networks are
really powerful. They can consumer just
one quick followup with this amazingly
profitable business. I think you dabbled
in buying some of the games and we have
um Bending Spoons coming on today uh to
talk about their aggressive acquisition
of not bad businesses but let's call
them slower growth businesses that maybe
Venture isn't um interested in. Is that
going to be a sustainable plan for you
to become a game studio? And does that
put you in conflict with the with the
partners?
>> Yeah, we we sold all those games. We
bought them originally as a data play.
We when we built our first deep learning
model, we needed to have data to train
it and game studios don't tend to want
to share data to third party companies.
So we bought our own studios, we seated
the training data in our first model, we
built a model that was really successful
in market, we started growing really
quickly. Once we started doing that,
third parties were coming in and we
divested that. What's the world of
advertising look like where um there's
agents everywhere, agents are servicing
you, maybe the human interface to
compute changes, so it's not necessarily
a computer that you're typing on or a
phone that you're browsing. Maybe it's
the meta glasses or some other device.
Um what role does the ad play and what
happens in this agentic commerce that so
many other people are trying to now push
into existence? Yeah, I mean I I think
the reality is part of the world will
start using things like agents to
optimize per certain shopper behavior
that's consistent. For instance, I might
put my supplement subscription into an
agent and have it optimized every single
month and deliver on time. But these
discovery platforms aren't that. And the
typical shopper is not the person who's
deep into agents and sitting on Twitter
and and adopting the latest technology.
I sort of say like our audience is the
New York Times audience. There's still a
ton of people using Yahoo properties
every single day. The typical shopper
wants to find a product and wants to
actually go through that shopper
behavior. They want to window shop. They
want to go through the transaction
experience.
>> They want to compare probably
>> totally. They want to track it. And if
you told them after the fact, hey, an
agent could have done this for you and
saved you 20%. I don't think that
matters on a $50 transaction because the
dopamine hit from going through it is
what they enjoy. So I I think there is
this part of the world that is
technologically advanced that's going to
adopt these technologies. I just don't
think I think we really overindex on the
Twitter verse and forget that the
average shopper is not that
>> yeah let me just try and understand how
you won because um the two of the
smartest companies in the world with the
best engineers Meta Alphabet Google make
most of their revenue from advertising.
They they've built their own models.
they've been doing it now for one to two
decades. Um, how did a small company
compete in this particular domain and
win? And what's the the operating model
that you think gives you an advantage to
continue winning?
>> Yeah, I mean, here's here's something
that that helped us get to this point.
We never think we won. We think every
day we wake up and we're probably going
to get screwed right now and we better
work hard. And so you've got a company
that's lean with a lot of subject matter
experts who are really really focused on
this thing, this mobile gaming
experience and translated into
transactional behavior on the other
side. And so I I I think there's this
ability to take on giants. If you're
very focused, you remain lean and you
can just move faster than them. And
>> what's the leakage in the business then?
So meaning when you look at a P&L, you
know, we did this I did this thing with
Amazon a decade ago where it's like you
look at all of these places in which
they were leaking and our big insight is
wow they just absorb these things and
they'll become the new businesses and
that was our long thesis for Amazon.
>> Yeah.
>> Um what's that version for you like
there there must be is it payment
infrastructure is it uh other kinds of
things Jason asked you about apps but I
guess you've divested that. So where's
the leakage or said differently where's
the opportunity for margin expansion so
that people underwrite this thing? Well,
our Ebidon margins I think are number
one in the market. It's 84%. So, I don't
know how much leakage we have. Yeah.
Given given the metric, but the the way
to think about it is advertiser comes
into our platform and they have a
transactional model. Let's say they're
selling lipstick. We give them an
arbitrage. They buy the they from us are
buying the consumer. That consumer
transacts and they cover the cost of the
consumer immediately. So, the consumer
buys the lipstick for 20 bucks. They pay
us less than the 20 bucks minus cost of
goods sold. They're happy. they scale up
and that performance model is very
scalable. Now our leakage is we're not
the full chain. We're not the advertiser
in the equation but we want to power the
advertisers to meet the consumer and
we've run extremely lean and been so
algorithmically focused and automation
focused that we haven't had a lot of
points of leakage.
>> The other side then is when you have 85%
EBIT to margins people say wow they
could be over earning. Right? That's the
classic phrase. And then you have
competition that says I can compete
Adam's margins away. I'm willing to do
this at 60% or 50%. But sort of maybe as
a correlary to David's question, that
hasn't really happened and it's been
incredibly sustained.
>> Yeah.
>> And why do you think that is?
>> Because these technologies are really
complex and if you can innovate and you
have differentiated data, you can build
an advantage. I mean by that token
anthropic shouldn't be running away with
the large language model space but the
power of a model that then reaches a
point of scale and gets adopted by a
large scale community becomes something
that is a a moat that is hard for other
people to overcome
>> and uh talk to us about this the team in
China and how big of an edge these folks
are. I mean, Chinese people are very
humble. They're very, very hardworking.
They're very sharp. And if you can work
with them, whether out of China or
United States or any other part of the
world, you're working with some of the
brightest minds in the world. And so,
uh, when I started the business, one of
my goals at this company was just work
with great people and figure things out.
And so, I'm when I sit in a room with
some of the people on my team, I know
I'm probably the dumbest person in that
room. And that gets me excited to show
up.
>> Got him. gets me to show up for the
>> feel when you hear that.
>> Yeah,
>> works for me.
>> All right, let's give it up for Adam.
>> Adam, thank you. Thanks, bro.
>> That was great. Thanks, man. Thanks,
man. Great to see you.